Guide to the William L. Taylor papers, 1954-2009 MS2287
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
William L. Taylor papers
1954-2009
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Taylor, William L.
MS2287
55.5 Linear Feet
This collection contains written speeches and testimony, correspondence, subject files, legal documents, and publications that William L. Taylor gathered and created during his career as a civil rights attorney between 1954 and 2009.
Biographical / Historical
William Lewis Taylor (October 4, 1931–June 28, 2010) was a lawyer and civil rights activist whose career spanned an extraordinary period in American civil rights history, from 1954 to his death in 2010 at age 78. For over five decades, he advocated tirelessly on behalf of African-Americans facing discrimination in education, housing, and voting, and played a key role in writing federal laws guaranteeing the rights of all Americans regardless of race. After graduating from Yale Law School in 1954, Taylor began his career working for Thurgood Marshall at the NAACP Legal Defense and Education Fund, assisting with civil rights cases in the wake of the Supreme Court's landmark 1954 decision in Brown v. Board of Education. In 1958, after the school board in Little Rock bowed to local resistance and suspended desegregation efforts, Taylor helped write the NAACP legal brief that persuaded the Supreme Court to require schools to comply with the Brown decision.
In the 1960s, as general counsel and staff director for the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights in the Johnson administration, he led the investigations into racial discrimination that laid the groundwork for the 1964 Civil Rights Act, the 1965 Voting Rights Act, and the 1968 Fair Housing Act. Soon after, he went on to found his own civil rights organizations, first the Center for National Policy Review at Catholic University, and later the Citizens' Commission on Civil Rights, where he focused on the implementation of federal civil rights laws and on school desegregation litigation. Since 1982, he also served as vice chair of the Leadership Conference on Civil and Human Rights in Washington, working to pass and strengthen civil rights legislation.
Most recently, Taylor focused his work on accountability in education, working to close the achievement gap in American schools and ensure a quality education for all students. He helped draft the 2002 No Child Left Behind legislation and defended it against challenges. He received the first Thurgood Marshall Award from the District of Columbia Bar in 1993, and the Hubert H. Humphrey Award from the Leadership Conference on Civil Rights in 2001.
In 2004 he wrote his autobiography, The Passion of My Times: An Advocate's Fifty-Year Journey in the Civil Rights Movement, in which he summarized his message to the next generation: "I want to convince people whose minds are open that the work of providing opportunity to those who are worst off in this society is not done. And I want to convince the pessimists that change is possible—that if the Kings and Marshalls could overcome the enormous barriers of the last century, modern advocates should not despair."
Arrangement
Collection: Organized into five series: Speeches and testimony; Correspondence; Subject files; Publications; and Photos
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Taylor family estate, 2010-2011 (Accessions 2010.059, 2011.011, and 2011.013).
Scope and Contents
This collection contains written speeches and testimony, correspondence, subject files, legal documents, and publications that William L. Taylor gathered and created during his career as a civil rights attorney between 1954 and 2009.
The material documents Taylor's work in the following roles in his long career: as an attorney for the NAACP, as general counsel and staff director of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights in the Johnson administration, as founder of the Center for National Policy Review at Catholic University, as founder of the watchdog group Citizens' Commission on Civil Rights, and as vice chair of the Leadership Conference on Civil and Human Rights. In addition, the material documents his work as an attorney in private practice, most significantly a longstanding school desegregation case, Liddell v. Board of Education of St. Louis.
Key topics in the collection include: school desegregation legislation (especially Title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act) desegregation litigation (especially the case of Liddell v. Board of Education of the City of St. Louis), affirmative action, and racial discrimination in housing and voting.
Law; Education; Civil rights; School integration; Segregation; Discrimination; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People -- Administration; United States Commission on Civil Rights -- Administration; Citizens' Commission on Civil Rights (U.S.) -- Administration
- Speeches and testimony, 1959-2009; Series 1; 9 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains handwritten speeches, typewritten testimony, and correspondendence related to speaking engagements from 1959 through 2009. In addition to testifying before Congress, Taylor frequently spoke about his work at conferences, universities, civil rights organizations, churches, embassies, and professional associations.
  - Testimony -- Staff Director and Commissioners, 1959-1968; Series 1 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Speeches and testimony, 1961-1962; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Speeches and testimony, 1963; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Speeches and testimony, 1964; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Speeches and testimony, 1965; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Speeches and testimony, 1966; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Speeches and testimony, 1967; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Speeches and testimony, 1968; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Speech to N.H. psychologists, 1969 April 25; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Speeches by others [1 of 2], undated; Series 1 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Speeches by others [2 of 2], undated; Series 1 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Resume, 1964; Series 1 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Bill Taylor speeches and testimony, 1972-75; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bill Taylor speeches and testimony, 1977-99; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Speech notes, 1983-85; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Talk at Grove City, 1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Danforth Education Law Seminar, 1985 February 15; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Talk to AARP Legislative Council, 1986 January 22; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Speeches and notes, 1986-88; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Paris: Symposium, 1988 June 09; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Southern Education Foundation Conference, 1988 November 02; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Panel at LDFJ Housing Conference at Airlie House, 1988 December 09; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bethesda United Church of Christ Church Breakfast, 1989 February 11; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Georgetown Conference on Affirmative Action, 1989; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Embassy of Israel reception in honor of Taylor, 1989 January 09; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Navajo education speech, 1989 March 02; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - River Road Unitarian Church speech, 1989 March 04; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sociological Evidence in Civil Rights Litigation, 1989 March 19; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Common Cause conference, 1989 May 05; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - ACLUF Conference, Oak Brook, IL, 1989 May 19; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1989 June 10; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Testimony before the Senate on the nomination of William Lucas, 1989 July 19; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures, Tulsa, OK, 1989 August 08; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - UCLA speech on fair employment, 1989 November 09; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - NAACP Legal Defence and Education, Airlie Conference, 1989November 16; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Claremont College speech, 1989 October 18; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, symposium on civil rights, 1989 December 06; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Georgetown University Law Center street law presentation, 1989 December 08; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Speeches and testimony, 1989; Series 1 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - Affirmative Government and Affirmative Action: What Works and Why, 1990 March 15; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - AFL-CIO Conference, New Orleans, LA, 1990 May 02; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Resolving Ethnic and Racial Conflict in the Workplace, Wausau, WI, 1990 May 24; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Library Association Conference, Chicago, 1990 June 24; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Sociological Association annual meeting, 1990 August 11; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Remarks on school finance consultation, 1990 September 14; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Department of Justice Civil Rights Division Speech, 1990 September 26; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ralph Neas G.B.S. Award Speech, 1990 October 03; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Women's Briefing Committee, 1991 January 13; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Harvard Symposium on School Finance speech, 1991 February 09; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Kern Alexander testimony, 1991; Series 1 (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Phoenix speech, 1991 March 13; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Forum of Educational Leaders, Institute for Educational Leadership speech, 1991 March 28; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - McGinty Show, 1995; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Clinton's Reform Agenda, Cubberley Auditorium, Stanford University, 1997 May 20; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - NRC Membership Bias Statement and Conflict, 1997; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Take Another Year, 1997; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Eisenhower Foundation -- Kerner Report, Taylor chapter, 1998; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - White House Medal of Freedom, 1998 January 15; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - LBJ School of Public Affairs, 1998 December 10; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Title I, 1999; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - ACE Symposium on Diversity, 1999 January 15; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - LCEF, Ad Council NY, 1999 February 19; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Statement on Reauthorization of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act, 1999 March 16; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Indiana State Teachers Association, 1999 April 07; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - PPI/Manhattan Institute, 1999 April 13; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Mock trial, 1999 April 15; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Operation Understanding Civil Rights Retreat, 1999 April 17; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - David Saperstein 25th Anniversary Dinner, 1999 April 26; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - American Educational Research Association, Montreal conference, 1999 April 21; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Transcript of DC Bar interview, 1999 April; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - LCCR conference, 1999 May 11; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Spotswood Robinson memorial, 1999 May 12; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Where's the Beef speech, 1999 May 20; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Stanford diversity conference, 1999 May 20; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Reflections on the Civil Rights Movement with Roger Wilkins, 1999 May 27; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - NAACP annual convention, New York City, 1999 July 14; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Woods Hole NAACP, 1999 July 07; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - National Advisory Council on Violence Against Women, 1999 August 15; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - American University summer institute on Racism in America, 1999; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Speech to California State High School Exit Exam Panel, 1999 October 15; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 24th Judicial Conference, 1999 June 03; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Federalist Society, 2000 November 18; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Washington Institute for Jewish Leadership and Values, 1999 December 06; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Judicial Conference, 2000 June 22; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Meridian International Center, 2000 January 17; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Operation Understanding, 2000 April 08; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Mock Trial Tournament, State v. Martha Monroe, 2000 April 06; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Teach for America, 2000 May 24; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - GRIPP/Applied research, 2000 May 19; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Millennium Conference, 2000 June 29; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Stanford project on affirmative action, 2000-01; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Superintendents' Work Conference, Columbia University, 2000 August 11; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Citizens' Commission on Civil Rights, New Orleans conference, 2000 September 20; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - BOTA Millennium Conference: Achieving High Educational Standards for All, 2000 September 21; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Kentucky Commission on Human Rights, 2000 November 09; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Old Westbury, Clarence Mitchell, Jr., 2001 January 30; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Urban Institute, 2001 March 06; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Teach for America, 2001 March 10; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - NAACP Strategic Task Force on Civil Rights Protection, 2001 March 17; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - House of Representatives, Education Reform Subcommittee, 2001; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Georgetown University, 2001 April 04; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights, 2001 April 05; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights dinner, 2001 May 09; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - LCCR Hubert H. Humphrey Award, 2001 May; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn College commencement, 2001 June 01; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Americans for Democratic Action panel, Promises Denied: Civil Rights in the Bush Administration, 2001 June 22; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - CCSSO Large Scale Assessment, 2001 June 26; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - U.N. World Conference on Racism, 2001; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, 2001 October 11; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Education Law Institute, 2001 October 17; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Airlie House, 2001 October 18; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Brooklyn College, 2001 October 21; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn College honorary degree, 2001; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - American Studies Association annual meeting, 2001 November 08; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Institute on Race and Poverty, 2001 November 09; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - PEN speech, 2001 November 12; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - PEN speech material, 2001; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Vanguard, 2001; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Housing Opportunity, Civil Rights and the Regional Agenda, 2001 November 16; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Invitations, Public Education Network, 2001; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Conference on Access to a Quality Education, 2000 September 20; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Southern Regional Education Board, Williamsburg, VA, 2001 October 12; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - NCREL, Napersville, IL, 2001 October 18; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn College, Alumni College Day, 2002 April 28; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Grantmakers for Education, 2002 April 29; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn College, 2002 May 30; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Civil Rights Project, Harvard University, 2002 June 18; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - DC Circuit Judicial Conference, 2002 June 12; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Litigation and Advocacy Directors Conference, 2002 June 23; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - College Board, California, 2002 June 24; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Hewlett Foundation California Education Reform Meeting, 2003 March 18; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - DC Public Schools/AU, 2003 April 16; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - National Education Association -- Brown v. Board of Education, 2003 May 12; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - K. Hakuta Racial Diversity Project, 2003 June 07; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - NAACP Brown Commission Meeting, 2003 June 26; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Color Lines Conference, Harvard University [1 of 3], 2003 August 29; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Color Lines Conference, Harvard University [2 of 3], 2003 August 29; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Color Lines Conference, Harvard University [3 of 3], 2003 August 29; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - PFAW materials for Color Lines Conference, Harvard University, 2003 August 29; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Notes, Harvard Color Lines Conference, 2003 September 01; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Alliance for Excellent Education, undated; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - NAACP Brown v. Board of Education Equity Commission meeting, 2003 October 22; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - The New School, 2003 October 22; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Airlie House -- Williamsburg, VA, 2003 October 23; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - International Visitor Program (Kazakhstan), 2003; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Yale Law School Alumni Weekend panel, 2003 November 01; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - National Coalition of Title I/Chapter I Parents Annual Conference, 2003 November 21; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - University of the District of Columbia, Brown v. Board of Education at 50, 2004 February 20; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Howard University Law School, Legacy of Brown v. Board of Education, 2004 February 28; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Memorial Service for Janice Kohn, 2004 March 05; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Washington D.C. Bar Judicial Conference, 2004 March 18; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Touro Law School, 2004 March 29; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - University of Maryland, 2004 April 01; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Yale Law School, 2004 April 02; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Bolling v. Sharp Symposium, Georgetown University Law School, 2004 April 15; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Elaine Jones dinner and reception, 2004 April 22; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - OSCE Conference on Anti-Semitism, 2004 April 28; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Poverty and Race Research Action Council executive committee hearing, 2004 May 11; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - LCCR Hubert H. Humphrey Awards Dinner, 2004 May 13; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Chicago Schools Policy Luncheon Series, 2004 May 13; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Washington D.C. Circuit Judicial Conference, 2004 June 15; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - LCCR Education Fund, OSCE Conference on Racism, Xenophobia, and Discrimination, 2004 August 18; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - LCCR Executive Committee meeting, 2004 September 09; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - PRRAC Board Meeting, 2004 September 10; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - CFE conference call, 2004 September 04; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Finley lecture, 2004 September 23; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Diversity Advancement Project, 2004 September 30; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 2004 invitations, Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Alliance for Excellent Education, 2004 October 03; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Affirmative Action Strategy Summit, 2004 October 15; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - NCLB: Developing a Common Agenda for Reform, 2004 November 11; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - LCCR National Board Meeting, 2004 December 1; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - LCCR Education Fund, 2004 December 3; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Embassy of Israel Civil Rights Leadership Awards, 2005 January 13; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Book tour, California, 2005 January 30; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - American University -- Mississippi Justice, 2005 February 16; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - LCCR Education Symposium, 2005 March 04; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Howard University education conference, 2005 March 11; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Charles L. Black for Yale Biographical Dictionary of American Law, 2005; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Yaki, Michael, 2005 March 16; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Alliance for Excellent Education, 2005; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Torture, 2005; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Wayne State University, 2005 March 29; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Operation Understanding, 2005 April 02; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Mock Trial Tournament [Street Law Judge], 2005 April 11; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - UNC Chapel Hill, 2005 April 13; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Judicial conference, 2005 April 27; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - PRRAC Board Meeting, 2005 May 13; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center, 2005 June 22; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Civil Rights Project, Changing NCLB District Accountability, 2005 June 24; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Speech to ADA, 2005 June 26; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - NAACP 96th Annual Convention, 2005 July 9; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - American Constitution Society, 2005 July 29; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Diversity Advancement Project, 2005 August 03; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - National Conference of State Legislators, 2005 August 16; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Larry Levine -- Conference, 2005 September 16; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - NYU School of Law, 2005 October 10; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Harvard Civil Rights Project, Hart Senate Office Building, 2005 October 14; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Center for American Progress, Obama speech, 2005 October 25; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Campaign for Educational Equity, 2005 October 25; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Lecture, WBA, 2005 October 26; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Airlie, Civil Rights Training Institute, 2005 October 27; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Title I Parents' Conference, 2005 November 03; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Association for Public Policy Analysis and Management Conference, 2006 November 02; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Turkmenistan visitors, 2005 November 29; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - LCCR, 2005 December 07; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Renaissance Weekend, 2005 December 29; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - King event, Israeli embassy, 2006 January 12; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Women's City Club, 2006 February 09; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Busboys and Poets, 2006 February 15; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - State Department Vienna DVC, 2006 February 26; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Turkmenistan delegates, 2006 March 02; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Hartford, CT, 2006 March 22; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Washington D.C. Judicial and Bar Conference, 2006 March 30; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Boalt Hall Symposium -- Rethinking Rodriguez, 2006 April 27; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Harvard Education Review, 2006 April; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Alaska Growth Model, 2006 April; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Washington D.C. Judicial Conference, 2006 June 6; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - American Constitution Society convention, 2006 June 16; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Aspen Institute, 2006 June 20; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - UK trip, 2006 July 1; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - NAACP testimony, 2006 July 07; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Superintendants Work Conference, Columbia Teachers College, 2006 July 09; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - LCCR Education Fund Board Meeting, 2006 July 21; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Voting Rights Act signing, White House, 2006 July 27; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Alliance for School Choice, 2006 August 02; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 15)